Tyler Swanson-Snead

702 West Casino Road Apt T302, Everett, WA. 98204 | (425)374-9257 | SwansonSnead.Tyler@Gmail.Com

Dear Hiring Manager:

I am writing in response to the position which is advertised as being open at this time. I am a talented Service Desk Technician/System Administrator working on service desks for over the last 7 years. Now I am interested in bringing my experience and abilities to work for your company.

My ability to work as a team player, meet deadlines and go the extra mile has contributed to my success. I've performed a variety of tasks and possess skills essential to support end users and maintaining necessary hardware and software critical to business functionality. I possess a unique talent for grasping technical information into terms and concepts that the end users can readily grasp.

I feel I can be a valuable asset to your team if given the opportunity. Please contact me if you would like to schedule an interview or if there are any questions about my skills or previous experience.

Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Tyler Swanson-Snead

Tyler Swanson-Snead

702 West Casino Road Apt T302, Everett, WA. 98204 | (425)374-9257 | SwansonSnead. Tyler@Gmail. Com **Professional Summary**

Exceptionally capable Service Desk Professional with years' experience in an enterprise environment troubleshooting complex end-user and hardware issues. Enthusiastically seeking to bring a vast repertoire of both hardware and software knowledge to a challenging position on a growing technical support team.

Education and Certifications

Associate of Applied Science: Computer Security and Network Technologies, 2012

Lake Washington Institute of Technology - Kirkland, WA

MCSA - Windows 10 - 2018 to Present

Skills

- Windows Server 2003/2008/2012/2016
- Windows XP/7/8/10
- Active Directory management and configuration
- Azure AD
- Microsoft Exchange Server
- Hardware deployments
- VoIP Telephony configurations and deployments
- Customer Service Expert
- Office 365 and SharePoint Administration

Work History

Fusiontek - Kirkland, WA

Systems Analyst, 1/2018 - Present

- Installed network hardware including firewalls, access points and servers.
- Configured and installed end user hardware and software applications.
- Migrations to Office 365
- Configured/Deployed VoIP telephony systems
- Performed data recovery and restores
- Troubleshoot and resolved client issues with in preset SLA's
- Created and maintained client documentations and processes.

702 West Casino Road Apt T302, Everett, WA. 98204 | (425)374-9257 | SwansonSnead.Tyler@Gmail.Com

Seattle Central College - Seattle, WA **Support Desk Tech II,** 5/2016 - 11/2016

- Imaged and Deployed staff workstations.
- Provided onsite support and resolutions for staff related issues and documented them in internal ticketing systems.
- Exchange migration team from legacy systems to hosted services. Set up new profiles/accounts on staff workstations.
- User account management adds/changes and password resets.

Arterian - Seattle, WA

Service Engineer, 7/2015 - 2/2016

- Provided Tier I & II support and resolutions for customer related issues utilizing internal ticketing systems for documentation.
- Answered/Resolved client trouble/service requests via inbound calls, e-mails and online ticket submission.
- Active Directory account creations, e-mail account creation/configuration, security and distribution group membership adds/moves/changes.
- Exchange migrations to hosted services.
- Performed Microsoft Server/Microsoft Windows updates/patching.
- Client LOB software/application configuration and installation.
- Data recovery and restoration.
- On-site hardware installations and troubleshooting/support.
- Regular on the On-Call rotation.

Fuse Networks LLC - Tukwila, WA Support Engineer, 5/2012 - 7/2015

- Provided Tier I & II support and resolutions for customer related issues and documented them in internal ticketing systems and knowledge base
- Answered/Resolved client trouble/service requests via inbound calls, e-mail and online ticket submission.
- Oversaw the daily performance of computer systems Windows XP/7/8 and Mac OSX in corporate/enterprise client environments.
- Imaged/Deployed new computer systems and ensured proper installation of cables, operating systems and software
- Created new user accounts and performed moves/adds/changes with-in Active Directory.

Tyler Swanson-Snead

702 West Casino Road Apt T302, Everett, WA. 98204 | (425)374-9257 | SwansonSnead.Tyler@Gmail.Com

- Created new MS Exchange accounts and Office 365 moves/adds/changes.
- Perform Moves/Adds/Changes on VoIP Mitel systems.
- Configured and repaired thermal label printers.
- Worked with service providers during site outages and escalated when needed to provision new network equipment.
- Traveled to client sites for installation of new hardware and various trouble shooting needs
- Participated in On-call after-hours rotation.

References

Available upon request